Uzair Shaikh

Mobile: +91 7385287790

Email id: uzair04shaikh@yahoo.com

Skype id:Uzair.shaikh04

Portfolio:https://uzair04.netlify.app/ **LinkedIn**: linkedin.com/in/uzair04shaikh

PMI Member ID: 6523971





Certified Agile Scrum Master

Career Objective

Looking for a challenging position in the industry to enhance acquired managerial & technical knowledge and skills towards the development of the organization.

Career snapshot:

Certified scrum master & PMP professional with result focused having 8+ years of experience in IT industry

- Overall 3.9 years of experience as Scrum master/Project co-ordinator
- Overall 5 years of experience in software development

Recenty cleared PMP examination from Project management institute.

Knowledge about software development life cycle(SDLC) that includes specifying and analysing requirements, release management

Expert at driving the adoption and enforcement of scrum rules, removing impediments and fostering self management

A desire to continually study new technologies and functionality, as well as be involved in projects that push the capabilities of existing technologies

Solid communication, collaborative and team building skills with acumen in training and supporting end users and technical staff to achieve performance objectives

In-depth customer-facing, relationship-building skills to interact directly with clients (onsite or offsite) and ensure continuity and customer satisfaction of services

Skill Set:

- Agile Principles
- Service delivery
- SAFe
- Kanban Model
- Requirement Gathering & Analysis
- People management
- Project management
- Process optimization
- Sprint planning meetings
- Strategic and Tactical planning
- Product development & deployment

Professional Experience:

Employer	Designation	Duration
Systems Plus Technologies, Pune	Senior Consultant	Sept 2017 – till date
Amdocs LLP	Sr Software Engineer	Dec 2014 - Sept 2017
Aptara New Media Pvt Ltd, Pune	Web Developer	Sept 2012 - Dec 2014

Overall responsibilities:

Identifying the requirements and documenting the business process.

Formulating excellent documentation on business requirements.

Managing various activities of the project such as information gathering, analysis, design and documentation.

Communicating with the stakeholders on behalf of the team as and when required.

Analyzing of different systems, document control and gaps in the process and systems.

Usage of Mockups, Data Visuation Product to have a better analytical view.

Responsible for Data model, reporting sytems, data automation systems.

PROJECTS HANDLED

System Plus

Title#1 Roundpoint's Mortgage project

Client Location USA

Role Scrum master

Accountabilities | Enabled sprint planning, daily scrums, retrospectives, stakeholders meetings.

Mainted focused on product backlog and project timeline with the development team and QA team through Kanban.

Assisted product owner in backlog management and continues delivery of features.

Providing release content notes to support wider communication for knowing the delivered features.

Providing release content notes to support wider communication for knowing the delivered features.

Preparing training documents for keeping the team up to date with latest change.

Handling Infrastructure Project including Data Center Migration, Disaster Recovery.

Environment Jira , Rally.

Amdocs

Title#2 AT&T Billing project

Client Location USA

Role Senior Developer

Accountabilities | Added the necessary responsive design for display and full functionality on tablet

and mobile.

Managed client relationships, project scopes, and time-lines.

Application worked across mobile devices (primary use case) and modern desktop

browsers.

Staging and Production release support.

Environment JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Title#3 AT& T Website

Client Location USA

Role Senior Developer

Accountabilities | Develop custom drop down, expand/ collapsed functionality and also configure the

screen to support the different browsers and devices.

Develop the drag and drop functionality.

Used Bootstrap in order to make it responsive and scalable to support different

types of devices.

Environment JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Aptara

Title#4 Mc-Graw Hill's White cotton

Client Location USA

Role Developer

Accountabilities | Translated design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive

features, using HTML/CSS and JavaScript

Developed the front-end web page by using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, taking

advantage of the frameworks.

Worked with browser compatibility issues.

Environment JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jquery

Title#5 Australian (CUP Melbourne)

Client Location | Australia

Role Developer

Accountabilities | Implemented plug-ins to extend application functionality.

Created security roles for strict control of UI elements and functions.

Performed testing and documentation of UI and services.

Worked on cross browser functionality.

Environment

JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jquery

Education Qualification:

Master of Computer Application (MCA)

College - Vishwakarma College of Arts, Commerce and Science, Pune

(Affiliated to Pune University)

Grade: First Class

Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)

College - Vishwakarma College of Arts, Commerce and Science, Pune

(Affiliated to Pune University)

Grade: First Class

Higher secondary certificate (HSC)

College: Poona College Grade: First Class

Secondary school certificate (SSC)

School: Dastur boy's school

Grade: First Class

Availibility:

Ready to relocate/join at the earliest

Do not have a bond with current employer

Personal Details:

Date of Birth : 4th September

Gender : Male

Languages known: English, Hindi, Marathi

Address: Legend Park, flat no 3, Inside Kubera Park, Lullanagar, Pune 411040

Passport Status: Ready